Guide to the Zora Neale Hurston Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Zora Neale Hurston Collection
1930-1972
JWJ MSS 9
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.8
(2 boxes)
The Zora Neale Hurston Collection contains Correspondence, Writings, including drafts of her autobiography, Dust Tracks on the Road, the novel, Their Eyes Were Watching God, and a play written in collaboration with Langston Hughes, "Mule Bone," as well as a study of Hurston written in 1972 by Robert Hemenway.
Hurston, Zora Neale, 1891-1960
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Zora Neale Hurston Collection contains items presented to the James Weldon Johnson Collection, principally by Hurston, with additional items from other persons.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
ZORA NEALE HURSTON (1891-1960)
Following an itinerant upbringing, Zora Neale Hurston focused on anthropology studies at Columbia University. Her ethnographic work, however, soon was overshadowed by her creative work, such as her collaboration with Langston Hughes on the play, "Mule Bone," and her novel, "Their Eyes Were Watching God." In later years, she was distanced from the original group of Harlem Renaissance writers, but a resurgence of interest about her in the 1970s and 1980s brought a new generation of readers.
Scope and Contents
This finding aid encompasses accessions of single manuscripts and small groups of manuscripts and other papers, by or pertaining to Zora Neale Hurston, which the library has chosen to group and list as an artificial collection.
African American authors -- 20th Century -- Archives; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967; Hurston, Zora Neale, 1891-1960
- Correspondence, 1934 Mar 26; Series I
  - Harmon, Ruby (Mrs. Cameron), 1934 Mar 26 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes copy of reply from "Mr. Johnson" To: 2 / From: 0
  - Jackman, Harold, 1933, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    To: 0 / From: 2
  - Van Vechten, Carl, 1930 Nov 14 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    To: 0 / From: 1
  - From Clark, Barrett H. to Carl Van Vechten, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Includes: carbon of letter from Clark to Langston Hughes
  - From Hughes, Langston to Carl Van Vechten, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - From Theatre Guild to Carl Van Vechten, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Writings, n.d.; Series II
  - "Are We Citizens", fragment, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Book of Harlem", short story, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "The Chick with One Hen," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8a)
  - Dust Tracks On A Road
    - Holograph manuscript, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Chapter drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1937, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Setting typescript, with printers notes (Box 1, Folder 11-14)
  - "The Emperor Effaces Himself," short story, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Harlem Slanguage", vocabulary, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Moses Man of the Mountain
    - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17-19)
  - "Mule Bone"
    (by Zora Neale Hurston and Langston Hughes)
    - Act One, mimeograph, 1931 Jan 26 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Now You Cookin' With Gas", short story, two versions (one incomplete): typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Tell My Horse
    - Holograph manuscript, with typescript additions and rewrites (Box 2, Folder 22-25)
    - Notes and miscellaneous pages (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Their Eyes Were Watching God
    - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 27-29)
- Other Papers, [1972]; Series III
  - "Zora Neale Hurston and the Etonville Anthropology" by Robert Hemenway, typescript, photocopy, [1972] (Box 2, Folder 30)